You came highly recommended--
the judge who exonerated
Odell Morgan.
She was impressed
by your tenacity.
She actually said
you're more like
a dog with a bone. but...
She knows that we're dying
for volunteers here.
Is that what got you interested
in the restorative justice
program?
The Morgan case?
Yeah.
The judge also mentioned
you were quiet.
So today. your job is to foster
dialogue and remediation
so that both the victim
and the offender
have a chance to heal.
You good?
Yeah.
Malik. hey.
This is Officer Torres.
Officer Torres.
Malik and his parents.
Troy and Carla.
How you doing. man?
Go ahead. shake the man's hand.
You can call me Dante.
I'm off duty now.
Mm.
Malik has now taken
full responsibility
for his actions and now has
the techniques to deescalate.
Correct?
Before an argument turns
into real-world violence.
Real world?
It all started
on their phones.
some social media beef.
Cam started it.
But you ended it. right?
Online. these kids say
whatever they want
with no consequences.
So Malik got in his head
that he was a big man.
He threw a Molotov cocktail
at Cam's fence.
and now we're here.
So we've come up with a plan.
Dante. you'll accompany Malik
to Cam's parents' house
and repair the damage.
Complete the circle.
All right. get your ass up.
Thank you. Dante.
Hey. don't let my son forget
that. back in the day.
this kind of thing
would have ended up
one of three ways:
jail time. a beatdown. or both.
Let's go.
Your dad. he's--
he's old-school. huh?
You don't believe in
restorative justice?
Car or a girl?
What?
The online beef.
You some kind of Jesus freak?
It's not Jesus.
It look like it to me.
St. Jude.
patron saint of lost causes.
Mm.
That's the kind of thing
a Jesus freak would say.
It was all lies.
what Cam was saying online.
I mean. it was about a girl.
but it was all lies.
Said I got no game.
Was it worth this?
Around here. you can't
let that disrespect slide.
People gonna treat you
like a bitch
for the rest of your life.
So yeah.
Okay.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
We're glad you've chosen
to make it right. Malik.
I know it's uncomfortable.
And we think restorative
justice is a great idea.
getting these boys to realize
the impact of their actions.
getting law enforcement
mixed in with community.
Makes everyone safer.
So. uh...
you got something to say?
Yeah.
Sorry I. you know.
burned your fence.
You know. everything.
All right. we'll get to work.
Let me know
if you need anything.
Thank you.
Hey. this looks awful.
What?
I mean. look at their fence.
Some crusty-ass pickets.
Our part looks too legit.
We got to fix the whole thing.
Relax. Jesus freak.
I'm not going to church
or anything.
I'm just saying.
If we do it.
we should do right.
Okay.
I'll get some more paint.
All right.
Hey! Malik!
No. No.
Oh. my God.
Offender fled in a blue
four-door Nissan.
I couldn't make out the plates.
but he was going eastbound
on 106th Street.
- Officer? Officer.
- I need cars right now.
Hey. don't step
on the sidewalk.
Oh. God.
Here. Oh. my God.
Is he--
- Step back.
Don't step on the sidewalk.
Is anyone inside hurt?
- Oh. my God.
Is he--
- Ma'am. listen to me.
They fired multiple shots.
Is anyone inside hurt?
- No.
No. sir. No. we're fine.
You sure?
- Police!
- Hands!
Let's see hands!
Hey. CPD!
I'm Intelligence!
Dispatch told you there was
going to be a plainclothes.
My badge is around my neck.
I'm taking it out.
Slow.
I need a perimeter.
All right?
They're not involved.
Here. hold pressure
on this. yeah?
Don't let anyone step
on the sidewalk.
Keep the pressure on.
Sir?
I know.
Just--just keep the pressure
until the EMTs arrive.
You don't call it.
You understand?
All right.
Shut down the block.
Get back inside.
They're going
to have to interview you
as witnesses.
No. patrol unit 506 is
holding down the scene.
I'm mobile canvassing
for the wanted Nissan.
I need a perimeter set 2 miles
out. so where are my cars?
- 10-4. 5021 Ocean.
Cars are en route.
Three minutes out.
Hey. move!
Come on!
5021 Ocean. I got eyes
on the wanted Nissan.
It's crashed just off
111th and Exchange.
Unknown if still occupied.
I'm approaching now.
Copy. 5021 Ocean.
Police!
Step out of the vehicle
right now!
Step out of the vehicle.
or I will shoot you!
5021 Ocean.
Any 5021 units available?
5021 Ida.
Ocean. go with your traffic.
- Yeah. I got blood.
- Torres got a scene.
Yeah. we just heard.
Offender appears
to be on foot
on 111th and Exchange.
I don't have eyes.
I need a perimeter.
a search team.
and I need cars right now.
All right. 10-4.
We're en route
from the district.
You got plates?
Nah. plates have
been stripped.
But I got the VIN.
Let me text you a picture.
Copy.
We'll run it on the way.
Hey. ma'am?
Police.
- Get in the house.
Hey. did you see anyone
come through here?
Did you see anyone
come through?
We didn't see anything.
Hey.
Hey. police.
Hey. sir. did you see
anyone come through here?
Anyone injured?
5021 Ocean.
I'm following a blood trail
into the Oakley Homes.
Five-oh!
Copy. 5021 Ocean.
Be advised. we have units
rolling your way.
- Five-oh!
- That's them!
That's them! Code 7!
That's them!
Yo. listen.
I'm not here for narcotics.
A kid was just killed.
and I'm looking
for the shooter.
Did you see anyone?
Anyone run up here. bleeding?
Listen. I got half a district
waiting for my signal.
So either you step up.
or they're coming in.
And they are gonna care
about that.
The roof.
Hey!
Cam!
Stop running!
5021 Ocean. offender fleeing
westbound on foot.
away from the Oakley Homes
housing project.
Suspect is male. Black. 6 foot.
wearing a green jacket.
identified as Cam Webb.
- Ocean.
- Yeah.
I ain't got nothing yet.
It's all clear past 120th.
and we got the perimeter
shut down.
Yeah. no sign of him. man.
You sure you got a positive ID?
It was him.
It was Cam Webb.
I saw him two hours ago.
He's the reason
Malik was even here.
Malik was trying to make
things right. apologize.
and then he got shot at.
I ran the VIN
on that vehicle.
Came back to Cam.
You checked the house?
The parents aren't
cooperating.
We got one shot to the head.
Several other rounds
hit sporadically.
All .380s.
Witnesses?
No. none that are talking.
Just you.
Yeah. I--I--
I didn't see anything.
I--my head was in the trunk.
getting some paint.
And then...
it happened in two seconds.
- Please!
- I want to see him!
Show me my son!
- I'm sorry. sir. you can't.
- I want to see my boy!
- I got it. guys.
Come on. show me my boy!
I want to see my boy!
Troy. Troy.
Hey. Troy. Troy.
- Show me my boy!
You remember me?
It's Dante.
Is that Malik?
Is that my boy? Is it?
Yes.
Is he dead?
Sir--
Your boy did this! Your boy!
- No. my son didn't do this.
- Your boy!
Where is he? I'ma kill him!
- Cam didn't do anything!
- He shot my kid!
Where is he?
- This wasn't my son!
No. where your boy at? Huh?
- No!
- Where is he?
Malik was here.
making it right!
- You ain't gonna touch my son!
- What'd your boy do?
Huh? What'd he do?
What'd your boy do?
Adam. get those people back
inside the house right now.
I'm telling you.
this wasn't my son!
Yeah. he did!
He shot my kid!
Hey. sir. you're the father?
Hey. hey. you're the father?
Yes? Sir?
- Yeah. I'm the father.
- Okay. Hey.
- Yeah. they killed my boy.
Okay. you can see your son
if you stop yelling.
You hear me?
Hey. look at me.
Sir. please stop yelling.
You can sit with your son
right now. okay?
You just can't touch him.
you understand?
You sit with him
as long as you need.
All right. you ready?
Come on. let's go.
Grab Burgess.
Go talk to the family.
I got you.
Come on.
I need you to be careful.
There's blood there. Okay?
We understand you are
trying to do your job.
But this wasn't our son.
Okay. okay.
Then help us eliminate him
as a suspect.
Where is he?
- We told you he's out.
- That is not an answer.
You know that
that's not an answer.
Cam didn't do this.
He would never do this.
What time did he leave?
Does he own a weapon?
Do you?
I saw Cam injured. fleeing.
I saw the blue Nissan.
Do you understand that?
What you saw was a Black man
in the Wild Hundreds
running from police.
That could have been anybody.
Green coat with a hood.
Does that sound familiar?
I saw him here when Malik was
trying to make things right.
You remember that?
That was social media.
That was just online--
Stop talking.
Okay. we can come back
with a warrant.
- Then do that.
- Okay.
Okay.
What happened to owning up
to your actions?
Don't act like
Malik was an angel.
Hey. enough.
We're done talking.
My family has
nothing else to say
without a lawyer present.
Nothing.
No sign of Cam.
We pressed.
Parents won't talk.
I mean. they're
protecting their kid.
They don't want to offer up
a timeline.
BOLO?
No hits.
Cam's cell phone's off.
CTA card's unused.
Kev's with Asset Forfeiture
putting out a financial alert.
All right. we run PODs
in the area?
Nah. CPD stopped
replacing PODs on that stretch
after gangs destroyed them
about a dozen times.
Neighborhood's owned
by the Gangster Prophets.
Runs deep.
We know Cam's affiliated?
He's indexed.
But the only charges
on his sheet are
driving without a license.
possession of paraphernalia.
I mean. his school records
are solid.
Just got a partial
scholarship to UIC.
He's a smart kid.
- Wow.
All right.
so what was the beef about
that got him involved
in restorative justice?
A girl.
Yeah. details are vague.
CPIC's still running it.
but it sounds like
Malik hit on the wrong girl.
Cam wrote to Malik.
"No place to hide.
Malik the Creep. Bang. bang."
And then. "Karma coming. bitch.
KYS for real."
- I'm sorry. what?
What is KYS?
- "Kill yourself."
- Yeah.
Yo. Cam's credit card
popped at a corner store
inside the perimeter.
The cashier said
he was banged up.
bought bandages.
left in a hurry.
This kid's got to be
hiding somewhere local.
No one in this neighborhood
is gonna talk.
No. not unless we make them.
All right.
so let's clear their sets.
We'll force it out of them.
Come on.
Me and you.
5021. all units in position.
Showtime.
I'll get behind them.
All right. cool.
Police!
- Chicago PD!
- Hey!
Everybody relax!
Come on! Here we go.
Over there.
Yeah. now turn around.
I got you. I got you.
You got anything on you?
Huh?
Got anything I need?
We wasn't even doing nothing.
Man. I saw you
throwing up gang signs.
That's disorderly conduct. boy.
Are you serious?
I was scratching my face.
- Ooh-whee.
All right. get him
to the wagon.
What's that?
VIP in the wagon. Here we go.
Take him in. Congratulations.
Man. whatever. dog.
We got one wagon
for you. boys.
Look. I don't mind the OT.
But Kiki wants to know
if I'll be home for dinner.
What are we doing. man?
Let me see.
Where are they taking us?
Indiana?
I need one more lap. Mikey.
I heard that one before.
Finna puke my guts up
in here.
Man. chill out.
They just trying
to wear us down so we talk.
But keep your mouth shut.
You know them police be having
them cells bugged. too. bro.
They just looking
for that boy.
I'ma beat Cam ass
for this. dog.
I seen him run up in
Shorty's spot an hour ago.
face all bloody.
What you talking about?
He ain't back with Shorty.
Tsk. I saw him at her spot.
You a sorry-ass simp.
He ain't even back with her.
Shut the hell up.
You can't sit in silence
for 20 more minutes?
Shut up.
You hear that?
Hiding at Shorty's.
CPD has 53 women documented
with the nickname "Shorty."
11 of them link
with the Gangster Prophets.
I'm still working
Cam's socials.
I don't think this kid went an
hour without posting something.
Damn near every girl he posts
about he calls "Shorty."
Right here.
I got one from July.
"Shorty at Reggie's beef.
Hooked it up
with the extra glizzy."
Yeah. I followed up
on that one.
The only girl working
at Reggie's at the time
didn't know him.
Do I want to know
what "glizzy" is?
Hold on.
There's an Instagram story
from six months ago.
Cam posted a link
to a baby registry.
Link's still up.
There's an address
for a Katherine Short--
1899 Framingham Avenue.
Katherine Short.
That's the neighborhood.
Okay. well. according
to Social Security.
Katherine Short gave birth
three months ago.
No father on
the birth certificate.
She's got no sheet.
She's 19 years old.
works as a hairdresser.
Cam's DM'd her.
He calls her "angel."
He ain't here.
Who?
You locked down all the sets
looking for Cam.
I ain't a idiot.
He ain't here.
So we can come in then?
- My baby's got to go down.
- It's okay.
I mean. if he's not here.
it's just gonna take
two minutes.
So you're saying
you're sure he isn't here.
I'm sure I haven't had
contact with Cam.
That ain't a thing
you can be unsure about.
You either spoke or you didn't.
He ain't hiding in
my fridge magnets.
- He didn't stop by today?
- No.
Are you aware of the beef
he had with Malik Hunter?
Don't try and catch me
on some motive.
Cam didn't kill anyone.
He wouldn't do that.
He's not a crap person.
He's got a life.
He's got people
that he cares about.
Like the two of you?
Yeah. you dick.
the two of us.
So you're the girl
that Malik hit on
and shouldn't have.
that started the whole thing?
Yo. are you done
searching yet?
Calm down.
What the hell is
taking so long?
We're just asking questions.
You come into my house.
You bother my baby.
- 'Cause a boy is dead.
- He wasn't no boy.
And he wasn't killed by Cam.
Get the hell off my property.
It was crammed underneath
the sink in the bathroom.
Glock 42. .380.
Where is he?
You don't understand.
Cam didn't kill anybody.
I--
Where is he?
I don't know. okay?
I don't.
My baby needs to sleep.
Get out.
Get out now.
I'm gonna need you
to give me the baby.
No. you're not
taking my baby.
And I'm not going anywhere.
Why am I here?
What did you bring me in for?
You didn't come into my house
with a warrant.
Why am I here?
You harbored
a wanted offender.
You lied to the police.
And you're in possession
of a murder weapon.
Cam didn't murder anybody.
I want my child.
I understand that. Katherine.
Your child is safe.
She is with your mother. okay?
And you will see her
as soon as you're released.
That will happen faster
if you cooperate.
You got to tell us
where Cam is.
I don't know.
He isn't some fugitive.
He's a wanted offender.
Do not say "offender" again.
Cam didn't murder anybody.
I saw him!
Torres.
Do you understand?
I saw him.
Hey.
My boobs are killing me.
I'm about to leak
all over this table.
Where did Cam run to?
You want to watch me
leak milk?
Is that why you signed up
to be police?
That make you feel big?
A 17-year-old kid was
shot down in broad daylight.
He will get justice.
You want justice
for that kid?
That little. innocent kid?
You're a fool.
Hey. ballistics
just came back on the Glock
and Cam's jacket.
It's the murder weapon.
Matches the slugs on scene.
And it's a street gun.
It links to four other
shootings in the neighborhood.
He used a street gun?
Yeah.
A local. dirty street gun?
Is this kid
that much of an idiot?
He used a gun that
we could trace back to him?
It is a strange rookie move.
Kid that grew up in the game.
you would think he'd be able
to get his hands
on a clean piece.
He did use his own car.
So. okay. I just got
an email from Forensics.
Cam's jacket came back negative
for gunshot residue.
Maybe he washed the sleeves.
No. the report would have
indicated that.
Well. we know
he was in the car.
Blood comparison's a match.
Dante. you saw him.
Fleeing.
I saw him fleeing.
When do I get to see my baby?
As soon as I release you.
All right. look.
I was with Malik
when he got shot.
He was trying to make
things right with Cam.
at least that's what he says.
Now. I do want justice
for that boy.
for his whole family.
But if Cam didn't kill him.
I want to help him too.
When somebody fires a gun.
it leaves an invisible trace.
It's called GSR.
And we ran
Cam's vehicle for it.
and we found plenty.
But it was all on
the passenger side. okay?
Nowhere else.
So somebody else fired the gun.
Somebody else was in that car.
Yeah. cool speech. buddy.
What have I been telling you?
I said he didn't shoot him.
Then who did?
I don't know.
Why do you keep saying
that Malik is not a kid.
that he's not innocent?
You keep saying that.
Wh--why?
Did someone else want him dead?
I just want to see my baby.
If Cam didn't kill Malik--
Yeah. but if Cam
is innocent--
Stop saying that.
You know he is.
He didn't kill anybody.
He didn't.
He calls her "Budbud"?
There were pictures
on your fridge.
He drew them?
For his daughter. Budbud.
Look.
Maybe I had it all wrong.
Tell me where he is. and I can
bring him back to you...
and her.
Katherine. where is he?
He'll hate me.
He doesn't have to know
the info came from you.
And I'll protect him
best I can.
Let me try and help him.
He's hiding
at a friend's house.
Marcus Everett.
Lives in the Wild Hundreds.
Everett's got a sheet.
Looks like a hitter
for the Gangster Prophets.
Stints for aggravated battery
with a firearm and drug distro.
Charges dropped in a homicide.
Witness recanted.
And he's a suspect
in two other shootings.
- This could be our shooter.
- Yeah. it's possible.
Everett lives alone
in a two-flat--
10439 102nd Street.
Let's hit it.
Wait. Kev. hold up.
Back door's already
been breached.
What?
How?
I don't know.
it's busted open.
All right. go. Torres.
♪ I can't help
but put a lot on myself ♪
♪ Understand how I feel.
not what I felt ♪
♪ 500 degrees get you melt ♪
♪ This swag water.
Michael Phelps ♪
♪ When they try to count me
out from the beginning ♪
♪ But I kept on going
and kept winning ♪
♪ Shots they be sending ♪
♪ And we all got a Benz ♪
♪ Yeah. I'm back
in the building ♪
♪ I'll be on my knees
praying ♪
♪ To God for forgiveness ♪
♪ Back to the business ♪
♪ Bad boy living ♪
♪ Lord be my shepherd ♪
♪ I can be my own witness ♪
♪ A life full of secrets ♪
♪ So I made her my mistress.
yeah ♪
Sarge. I'm opening
the door now.
Got it. Go.
Hey!
Troy!
He took my son away.
Let him go.
Listen to me.
- He took my son away!
- You don't want to do this.
You don't want to do this.
- Over a fence!
Over social media!
I don't think he did. Troy.
Listen to me.
I don't think he did.
Don't mess with me!
I'm not messing with you!
Listen to me.
Drop it right now.
He was hiding here.
He was gonna run.
He was just gonna slip away.
- Troy--
- Hey!
- He killed--
You all right?
You okay?
I did it.
I shot him.
I shot Malik.
I told you.
I told you he killed him.
I confess.
I shot him.
I'm telling you.
I don't need to be down here.
You can book me.
There's no cameras down here.
All right?
That's why you're here. 'cause
you keep falsely confessing.
I'm not falsely confessing.
I killed Malik.
I shot him.
All right?
I confess.
Look. we could take you
back to Med.
I don't need it.
Just--just book me.
We're not booking you.
We know there was
another person in your car.
Was it Everett?
No.
I killed him.
I shot Malik.
I confess. okay?
All right. then tell us
how it happened.
- What?
- How you shot him.
I took a few shots
through the window.
Hmm.
We tested your jacket
for gunshot residue.
It came back clean.
I fell.
You fell?
Slipped in a puddle.
It must have just
washed it off.
I don't know.
Where'd you get the gun?
Crackhead down on 42nd.
We traced the gun
back to the Gangster Prophets.
It was a local street gun.
not 42nd.
Katherine Short says
you didn't kill him.
She's hormonal.
She'll say anything.
I killed him.
I shot Malik.
- Cam--
I confess.
I killed him.
I shot Malik.
I confess.
I killed him.
I shot Malik.
I confess.
I killed him.
I shot Malik.
I confess.
He's just repeating
his confession.
It's like he wants this
to be over.
He could be
scared of someone.
protecting someone.
- Anything from Troy?
- No.
He heard about
where Cam was hiding
the same way we did--
street contact.
Hasn't heard
any more information.
Shorty?
No. she won't say
anything else.
She finally lawyered up.
and she's got a good alibi.
Yeah.
Marcus got an alibi too.
I ran it. It's bulletproof.
We got him on footage
at a bar halfway across town
during the time
of the shooting.
He wasn't in Cam's car.
So we're missing something.
Well. it's simple.
We go back to the why.
Why the hell was
Malik shot down?
The why will always
get us to who.
All right. so we split it up.
Go down every path again.
Let's go.
There's 48 posts
between Cam and Malik.
but not a single post
between Malik and Shorty.
She's not the girl he hit on.
Why'd you go to that program?
Restorative justice?
I was asked.
Well. that doesn't sound
like a real answer.
It's a nice idea.
that people can be restored.
Hmm.
Wait. come here.
I think that's Iyana.
Cam's sister?
Yeah. she's using
a dummy name.
She was following Malik
on social media.
and they posted back and forth
until the day before
Cam started talking trash.
What the hell
happened that day?
Fresh ice.
Are you booking me yet?
- Nope.
- Why?
I don't know how many more
times I can confess.
About three months ago.
Malik and Iyana
began interacting on Instagram.
And eventually.
they met up in person.
The day after they met up.
Iyana went to a medical clinic.
and she got treated
for injuries
consistent with sexual assault.
Now. the medical clinic
was obligated
to report the injuries.
but they didn't.
So I spoke to the doctor
that treated her.
and she said
that Iyana insisted.
She said she got
in a fight with a friend.
and she begged them
not to tell.
The next night. you posted
a story threatening Malik.
That's right. I did.
I threatened him.
And I was the one
that shot him.
So don't bring my sister
into this.
We traced the gun
that was used to kill Malik.
The last Gangster Prophet
that sold it.
he confirmed
he sold it to Iyana.
She bought it for me!
Cam. we found gloves
and a jacket in her locker.
It tested positive
for gunshot residue.
We have evidence.
I--I should have
taken care of it myself.
She told me what happened.
and I...
didn't know what to do.
I went online.
I threatened Malik.
But I--I should have done more.
He kept saying things back.
I should have known she would--
I get it.
Then. please...
please let me take the time.
- I can't do that.
- Yes. you can.
Have the evidence disappear. right?
Say--say it was me.
She bought the gun for me.
Look. I can do the time.
She can't.
She ain't strong like that.
The jury will go easy on her.
and she won't be tried
as an adult.
Juvie's just as bad!
Let me do the time.
She's the victim here!
Do you get that?
She took a life.
He took from her!
I know.
Then help me.
We can end this the right way.
Just let me save
my little baby sister. please.
Please.
I will help Iyana
as much as I can.
I promise you that.
But that's the best
that I can do.
I'm sorry.
More police?
This can't be legal.
You can't just sit here
and not tell us anything.
It's lawful detainment. sir.
Nah. you can't
just hold us here.
My daughter needs
to go to school.
We have work.
We have rights. man.
Please tell us you're here
to stop this nonsense
and let this child
go to school.
Iyana. I'm Officer Torres.
I'm here to arrest you
for the murder of Malik Hunter.
I need you to stand up
and place your hands
behind your back.
- What? What?
- No. no. stop.
- Gerald--Gerald.
- What's going on?
Stop. What are you doing?
- Iyana--
- What? No. we need our lawyer.
- What's happening?
- Daddy--
- The lawyer is on his way.
Right now.
I need you to stand up
and place your hands
behind your back.
Get away from her!
Iyana. look at me.
We're going to do this
one thing at a time. okay?
Can you do that for me?
Stand up.
Now. just give me your hands.
Hold them up for me.
What's happening?
- Stop.
Why are they putting cuffs
on my baby?
What happened?
They're gonna--we're gonna be
right behind you.
It's okay.
Where are they taking her?
Where are you taking her?
Can we come. please?
Baby. don't worry!
Okay. now can you turn
to the other side. please?
Iyana?
Could you turn
to the other side. please?
Now face the front.
Hey. it's okay.
Iyana. could you look up
for me. please?
All right.
We can wait here
until they arrive.
Have a seat.
Are your hands hurting you?
Here.
What's gonna happen to me?
When you get inside.
you keep your head down.
Okay?
You try not
to draw eyes on you.
You understand what I mean?
You listen to the correction
officers who are nice.
and you stay far away
from the rest.
You don't fight. ever.
And if you have a problem.
you contact your lawyer.
or you contact me.
You got that?
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today